<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-14T15:38:40-06:00</updated><id>https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Learning Deep Learning</title><subtitle>This is my journey in trying to make sense of deep learning.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Introduction to deep learning(3rd Semester)</title><link href="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/markdown/2021/01/15/Introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to deep learning(3rd Semester)" /><published>2021-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/markdown/2021/01/15/Introduction</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">Recently I came across a deep learning course that has changed my life forever!!! I am talking about fast.ai’s FastAI “Practical Deep Learning for Coders”. First misunderstanding: Deep Learning only for PhDs I started deep learning in my 3rd semester minor project(currently in 6th semester) and I went through a lot of courses on youtube and coursera. At first, it was very exciting to know the maths behind all of this but when I tried to implement it I was unable to do so. I found myself searching tutorials and guides for tensorflow, keras, pytorch but nothing made sense. I was frustrated as I was unable to implement something which I understood. For example, the project that I was working on had the equation for the prediction as y(m,t) = Σσ1(b+mew1) * σ2(b-tew2) * ew3 where σ1 is softplus function and σ2 is a sigmoid function. The above equation clearly states that I have to create all these layers from scratch since all the predefined models do computation of the form b+(some input)*w. Making above architecture seemed so difficult to me and I came to the conclusion that only PhDs understood intricacies of deep learning. So, at last I went to tensorflow keras tutorial, randomly added lots of dense and embedding(lol, it didn’t require any embedding layer, I didn’t even know back then what an embedding layer was) layers for this model, got an accuracy so bad(mape of 1 lakh) and lost all interest in deep learning. Second misunderstanding: More epochs means more accuracy I remember I used to train the above model for 250 epochs(lmao, its funny now that I know) and leave my laptop for hours thinking that the error would decrease. After taking the fast.ai course, I’ve come across exceptional accuracy by training for only 3 epochs. That is why 250 seems a very large number. So that was my introduction to deep learning which was not very pleasant as evident.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fastpages Notebook Blog Post</title><link href="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/jupyter/2020/02/20/test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fastpages Notebook Blog Post" /><published>2020-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/jupyter/2020/02/20/test</id><author><name></name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/images/chart-preview.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/images/chart-preview.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Example Markdown Post</title><link href="https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/markdown/2020/01/14/test-markdown-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Example Markdown Post" /><published>2020-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://anubhavm55.github.io/Jupyter_Notebooks_Blogs/markdown/2020/01/14/test-markdown-post</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html">Example Markdown Post</summary></entry></feed>